Yu, you've got to eat.
小予 吃点东西吧
Mom, I'm not hungry.
妈 我不饿
Saw you didn't take notes in physics class.
刚才物理课你没记吧
Take mine, and copy it down.
拿去抄吧
[You're welcome.]
不用谢
Defense! Stay active.
防守 积极点
Box out!!
把位卡住
Inside.
内线
Nice, nice!
漂亮 漂亮 漂亮
Good job!
很好
Rebound!
篮板球啊
Good.
好
Create space!
空档 注意拉开空档
Why didn't you catch my pass?
刚才为什么不接我球
Yo!
唉
Come on, pass the ball!
来 传球
Ma Yiming.
马一鸣
You two still haven't reconciled?
你们还没和好呀
Let's not bring up this subject.
别说了
I don't know when that punk
臭小子不知道什么时候
became so stubborn.
变那么死心眼
What's that saying?
那句话怎么说的来着
Something begins with "L"  clouds judgment.
那什么让人丧失理智
So what do we do now?
那现在怎么办
The best way to solve this
现在最好的办法
is to find evidence
就是去找证据
to prove that someone else is responsible.
证明这件事另有其人
But how?
怎么找啊
Shh!
嘘
Right now, anyone
我们现在周围
that we see around us
任何一个人
could be the perpetrator.
都可能是凶手
We need to find
所以我们要找一个
someplace quiet.
绝对隐蔽的地方
Since that article was posted on the
那既然这篇文章一大早
bulletin board early in the morning,
就贴到了公告栏上
does that mean the perpetrator
那是不是就说明
posted it in the middle of the night?
这个人是大半夜贴的呀
Even if we know
那就算咱们知道
it was posted in the middle of the night,
是大半夜贴的
we still can't
那咱们也不能
pinpoint the perpetrator.
锁定目标啊
There's another way.
还有一个办法
What is it?
什么办法
Xu Mengyu said she didn't
徐梦予说过
bring too many samples to school,
带来学校的样书不多
so she definitely knows
所以给了哪些人
who she gave them to.
她肯定知道
We just need to
我们只需要
find those people
把那些人找出来
and see who's missing
然后看看谁缺少了
the page that was plagiarized,
抄袭的那一页
and that will be our guy.
谁就是我们要找的人
[Mengyu,]
梦姐
[we've been waiting for you to come back.]
我们都等你回来呢
[I've taken all the notes for]
今天上课的笔记
[today's classes for you.]
我都给你记好了
[Mengyu,]
梦姐
[if you need to talk, I'm all yours.]
你有什么话可以对我说啊
[are you coming today?]
那你今天来吗
[Mengyu,]
梦姐
[will you be back tomorrow?]
你明天会回来吗
[I'm at the subway exit near your house.]
我在你家楼下地铁口
[Can we meet?]
能见个面吗
Mengyu.
梦姐
OK,
说吧
what is this about?
什么事
I just wanted to see you.
我就想来看你一眼
Now you've seen me.
现在看见了吧
You may leave.
你可以走了
Xu Mengyu,
徐梦予
I heard you'll transfer to another school.
听说你要转学啊
Could you please stay?
能不走吗
What does that have to do with you?
这跟你有什么关系
Once when I was in my freshman year,
高一的时候
I told the teacher that
我跟老师说
my homework was blown away by the wind.
我作业被风刮走了
Actually, I didn't do it.
其实是我没写
And there was another time I came in late.
还有一次我迟到了
I told the teacher my stomach hurt.
我跟老师说我肚子疼
Actually, I didn't get up in time.
其实我没起来
Also, during an exam,
还有一次考试
I looked at someone else's answers...
我看了别人答案
So you're saying,
所以你是想说
plagiarism is no big deal, right?
抄袭没什么大不了是吗
I'm trying to tell you,
我是想跟你说
everyone makes mistakes.
其实每个人他都会犯错
We did in the past,
以前会犯
and we will in the future.
那以后也会犯
We'll make many, many mistakes.
会犯很多很多错误
If we make mistakes, we acknowledge them,
错了就知错
and we stop making them again.
咱们改了
No big deal.
就没什么大不了的
Am I right?
对不对
A single mistake
一次错误不能成为
is not a lifelong stain.
你人生的所有
If
如果
you're aware you've made a mistake
你明明知道自己犯了错
and still continue to hide
还要在安全屋里
and avoid facing it,
继续逃避面对的话
then that's truly shameful.
那才是真正的可耻
You should go home.
你回家吧
[Dear faculty and my fellow students]
辰郡中学的各位老师
[of Chenjun High School,]
同学
[I am Xu Mengyu.]
我是徐梦予
I am here
我在这里
to apologize to you all.
是想给大家道歉
I'm sorry, I plagiarized.
对不起 我抄袭了
[All these days,]
这么多天
[I've been asking myself]
我一直反复问自己
[what the meaning of my writing is.]
我写作的意义是什么
[Is it for the]
是为了获得
[so-called vain praise,]
所谓虚荣的赞美
[or to express myself?]
还是表达我自己
[But in the glory and praise,]
但是在荣誉和赞美中
[I lost my true self.]
我迷失了自己的本心
[I lost myself.]
我把我自己弄丢了
[But I'm fortunate that]
但是很庆幸
[I still have the chance to make amends,]
我还有机会弥补
[to find my true self again.]
还有机会找回自己
[There are no shortcuts to success.]
成功没有捷径
[I can only put in double efforts.]
只有付出加倍的努力
[I've let down everyone]
我愧对学生会的
[in the student union,]
所有同学们
[and set a bad example for all of you.]
做了不好的表率
[So starting today,]
所以从今天开始
I'll resign from
我会辞去
all my positions in the student union.
学生会的所有职务
I apologize again to all the students
再次向所有同学
and faculty.
老师道歉
I'm truly sorry.
对不起
Mengyu is back.
梦姐回来了
You're back.
回来了
Mengyu!
梦予
Mengyu, you're finally back!
梦予 你可算回来了
Where have you been?
你去哪儿了
I thought you transferred.
我以为你转学了
You really scared me, you know?
急死我了你知道吗
It's OK. I'm back now, aren't I?
没事 我这不回来了吗
It's good you're back.
回来就好
I'll help you with your backpack.
我帮你拿书包
Hello, everyone.
大家好
I'm back.
我回来了
Xu Mengyu,
徐梦予
you misunderstood Xiao Xiaohua.
你误会肖小画了
She's not a
她不是一个
two-faced person.
两面三刀的人
If you really want to find the one
如果说你一定要找到
who stabbed you in the back,
那个贴公告栏的人
it's simple.
很简单
This is Xiao Xiaohua's book,
这是肖小画的书
and it's intact.
很完整
The missing page is page 35.
缺的那页在第三十五页
Whoever's is missing it, did it.
谁缺了谁干的
Mine is here!
我的在呢
Who else has got it, bring out yours.
还有谁都拿出来
Good thing I brought mine.
幸亏我带了啊
Page 35, I've got it.
三十五页 我也在
I brought mine too.
我的书也在呢
I wasn't given one at all.
压根没发给我
Then the rest of you,
那剩下的人
bring out your books.
也都把书拿出来
Let's take a look.
比对一下
Please stop!
都别找了
I don't want to know who that is.
我不想知道这个人是谁
Why?
为什么
Have you heard what's
你不知道大家
been going around about you?
怎么说你的吗
Because I am aware of it,
就是因为我知道
I don't want that person
我不想让那个人
to go through
再经历一遍
what I've been through.
我经历过的
Whether it was me
是我也好
or not,
不是我也好
nothing will change now.
什么都已经改变不了了
And Mengyu
而且梦予
has paid the price
也为她的过错
for her mistake.
付出了代价
I agree with Xiaohua.
我同意小画说的
That person hasn't done anything wrong.
那个人没有做错
I'm the one at fault.
错的是我
Even if he hadn't exposed all this,
就算他没有说出来
I would still have been wrong.
我还是错了
Let's put an end to this.
这件事情就到此为止吧
Mengyu, welcome back.
梦予 欢迎回来
Mengyu,
梦予
glad you're back.
欢迎回来
Mengyu, welcome back.
梦予 欢迎回来
Xu Mengyu, it's good to have you back.
徐梦予 欢迎回来
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Do you remember what you told me
你还记得你上次在天台
on the rooftop last time?
对我说的话吗
Yes.
记得
Actually, last time on the rooftop,
其实上次在天台的时候
I was so scared that
我很担心这个事
this would be discovered by others.
会被别人发现
I was scared every day.
每天都会害怕
I was scared that the lie
不知道这个谎言
would be exposed someday.
什么时候会被戳穿
The more I hid,
越是隐瞒
the more I lost the courage to confess.
越是丧失了坦白的勇气
But you came back anyway.
但是你还是回来了呀
So,
所以啊
you're not a coward.
你并不是一个懦弱的人
I thought when I came back this time,
我以为我这次回来
everyone would blame me,
大家会指责我
look down on me,
会看不起我
but I didn't expect them to
但是没想到他们
accept me again.
都重新接受了我
I was quite surprised
我还挺意外的
and touched.
也很感动
Sometimes the hardest thing
有时候其实最难过的
is actually your own inner struggle.
是自己心里那一关
When you muster the courage
当你鼓起勇气
to take that step,
迈出那一步的时候
you'll find that things aren't as scary
你会发现事情并没有
as you imagined.
你想象中那么可怕
I also want to say
我还要跟你说一句
sorry to you.
对不起
I've wanted to tell you this for a while,
这句话我想说很久了
and today I finally said it.
今天终于说出来了
You're right,
你说得对
taking this step
迈出这一步
doesn't seem as hard as I thought.
好像没有想象中这么难
Xiaohua,
小画
have you ever thought
你有没有想过
that if we don't find out
如果一直不找出
who that perpetrator is,
那个人的话
everyone might think
可能大家都会觉得
you're the two-faced person
你就是那个两面三刀
who drove Xu Mengyu away?
逼走徐梦予的人
Then for the rest of this term,
然后今后的一年
both of us
我们两个
will be affected by you.
就都会被你连累
Hey!
好啊
So you two
你们两个
were actually not doing this for me,
居然不是为了我
but for yourselves?
是为了你们自己
Isn't that obvious?
可不是吗
I have no idea
所以我就不清楚
what's going on with
你这脑回路
your thought process.
到底是什么情况
I knew that you two
我知道你们俩
were doing this for me,
是为了我好
but I believe that person
但是我相信那个人
didn't have any ill intentions.
他并没有恶意
He just didn't have the courage
他只是没有勇气
to point it out.
当面指出来而已
Actually, I was the same.
其实我跟他也一样啊
I was also aware that
我不是也知道
Xu Mengyu plagiarized,
徐梦予抄袭
yet I chose not to speak up.
但也没有指出来吗
So what are you,
所以你这个
if not a saint?
不是圣人是什么呢
I don't care if this is saintly
我才不管这是圣人
or whatever.
还是什么呢
I just did
我就是这样想
what I thought was right.
就这样做了呀
Everyone has their own way
每个人都有自己
of dealing with problems.
处理问题的方式
It might not be right,
那可能不对
and you might regret it,
也可能会后悔
but who knows?
那谁知道呢
Being accepted is easy,
被接受是容易的
but sometimes,
但是有的时候
being disliked for being yourself
为了做自己而被讨厌
also takes courage.
也同样需要勇气的
Alright then,
行吧
no matter what comes next,
不管最后结果如何
I will firmly stand by
我都会坚定地站在
your side, apprentice.
徒弟你这边
So will Ling Dong.
还有凌冬
I have my doubts on this,
我持保留意见啊
but still,
不过
I'm willing to stand by your side.
还是愿意跟你们一路的
Xiaohua, I'm sorry.
小画 对不起
Ling Dong,
凌冬
sorry to you as well.
也对不起
Yo, aren't you apologizing to me?
我呢
We're buddies. That won't be necessary.
跟你还说什么对不起
[Finally escaped from]
终于逃脱出
[the cage that bound me,]
束缚自己的牢笼
[shattered the mask,]
打碎假面
[and found that cowardly self.]
找到了那个懦弱的自己
[For the first time, I felt]
第一次感觉到
[the breeze on my face]
微风吹在脸上
[also had a sweet taste.]
也有甜甜的味道
[Let's get to know each other again.]
重新认识一下
[Hello, Xu Mengyu.]
你好 徐梦予
[You were meant for something great.]
你生来就是个大人物
[You just need to endure some hardship.]
只不过需要暂时吃点苦
[Keep it up, Xu Mengyu.]
加油 徐梦予
Dream Rider?
以梦为马
Stay focused, guys.
都认真点啊
Look at you.
看你们这一个一个的
Aren't you usually quite noisy
平时在教室里
and active in the classroom?
不挺欢实的吗
Why are you all so lethargic out here?
这出来怎么都蔫儿了
I have an announcement.
跟大家宣布个事啊
The basketball tournament
咱们学校的篮球比赛
has been scheduled,
时间已经定了
and it's next week.
就在下周
Sir, our PE classes
老师 我们的体育课
have all been replaced by other classes.
都被其他课给占了
How are we supposed to train for it?
这哪有时间训练
It would be like asking for humiliation.
上场不是找虐呢吗
Hey, you are a teenager.
不 你年纪轻轻的
Man up, OK?
你有点自信好不好
For such an energetic
这么热血
and passionate sport,
又有激情的运动
is there anybody willing to step up
你们班谁毛遂自荐
and organize for it?
来组织一下啊
Finals are coming. You won't have time.
快期末 你没时间
No volunteers. I'll appoint someone then.
没人来我可点名了啊
Lan Jinghui.
兰靖灰
Here!
到
You and Ma Yiming will be
你跟马一鸣一起
in charge for the task.
负责你们班的篮球队
Aye aye, sir!
是
Guys, feel free to exercise on your own.
大家自由活动一下吧
Alright, fellas,
好 同学们
our school's basketball tournament
咱们学校的篮球联赛
is coming soon.
马上就要开始了
Let me briefly explain the rules.
我先简单说一下规则
The participants in this tournament
咱们这次比赛
will include students from
由高一和高二的
all classes in Grades 10 and 11.
所有班级组成
Each class will field five players.
每班出五名队员
If there are not enough players,
如果人数不够的话
you will be considered a forfeit.
按弃权处理
The tournament will be knockout-based.
比赛采用淘汰制
In a moment, we will draw lots to decide
一会儿会抽签来决定
who your opponents will be.
你们的对手是谁
Any questions?
还有什么问题吗
No!
没有
If not,
没有的话
let's start drawing lots.
咱们开始抽签吧
Yours first.
你们班开始
Dismissed!
解散
Yo, Lan Jinghui,
我说兰靖灰
these are all you've got?
你们班就这么几个人
Didn't you hear the teacher?
你刚没听教练说吗
If the players are not enough,
参赛人数不够
it's considered a forfeit.
直接视为弃权
How embarrassing would that be?
这样你说多可惜啊
How about this,
要不我说
just withdraw from the tournament.
你们直接退赛得了
Just save yourselves the embarrassment
到时候人数不够上场
for not having enough players.
多尴尬
Bi Peng, for your information,
毕鹏啊 我跟你说啊
even though we're short on numbers,
别看我们班现在没人
any one of us
但是
could beat all of you
随便挑一个人
by dribbling with
都能用小拇指头
just a pinky,
打爆你们班的所有人
like this.
这么运球
If you're short on numbers, just admit it.
没人就没人呗
Why pretend to be a big shot?
装什么大尾巴狼啊
If you don't make to the preliminaries...
省得到时候进不了预赛
Alright,
行了
just give your best shot.
加油吧
Don't get eliminated in the first round.
别到时候初赛就淘汰了
If that happens, our teams won't be able
咱们班 还有你们班
to face each other during the finals.
无缘总决赛
Save your bluffs,
大话不要说得太早
or, you'll embarrass yourselves later.
不然到时候丢人现眼
What's the smell?
什么味这么大
Do you smell it?
你闻着了吗
There's a cumin smell.
有股孜然味呢怎么
Seems like there is.
好像是有点味
You reek, dude!
你这味道也太大了吧
Cut the bull!
你少胡说八道啊
I was not BSing.
我没胡说八道啊
Hey pal,
我说兄弟
there's no denying that
咱们练篮球累归累
playing basketball is exhausting,
对不对
You've got to attend to your hygiene.
个人卫生你得注意
Exactly!
就是
That's not good.
不好啊
Attend to it.
是不是得注意
Right?
是不是
Apply some bleach.
多用点洁厕灵洗一洗
Bleach wouldn't be effective.
洁厕灵洗不干净
[He's got to use disinfectant.]
得用84消毒液
[That works too.]
也行
[Goodbye,]
再见
[barbecue boy.]
烧烤男孩
[He's cumin boy.]
孜然男孩
No smell.
没味啊
[That works too.]
也行
Jiang Jing,
蒋净啊
would you consider being a forward?
前锋考不考虑一下
A forward
前锋呢
is someone being
就是指冲在我们这个
at the very front
篮球队伍里面
in our basketball team.
位置里面最前
I really have to work on this problem.
这道题我得好好解一下了
Hey, Chen Yu.
陈宇
What's up, Jinghui?
怎么了 灰哥
About the point guard position,
得分控卫这件事
what do you say?
你怎么说
Let me tell you...
我跟你讲啊 你
Jinghui,
灰哥
I might have a stomachache later.
我过两天肚子可能会疼
Hey!
不是
Jinghui,
灰哥
I'm starting to feel it.
来感觉了
I'm starting to feel it, man.
来感觉了 灰哥
It hurts so bad.
太疼了
Wu,
小吴啊
even though you're wearing glasses,
别以为你戴眼镜
I could tell that you're capable of...
我就看不出你会
Hey, Wu,
小吴 小吴
where are you, Wu?
小吴 你在哪儿 小吴
Wu?
小吴
Mo Fei,
莫非啊
I know you are...
我知道你
Jinghui,
灰哥
You were just looking for Wu, right?
你刚刚找小吴呢
You should have told me earlier.
早说呀
I'll help you find him.
我帮你去找他
[Where did you go, Wu?]
小吴 你去哪儿 小吴
[Wu?]
小吴
[Zhu Ming...]
朱明
[Yo, Wu!]
小吴 小吴 小吴
[Wu?]
小吴
Ruosi.
若丝
I remember the advisor
我记得班主任
asked me to do something.
叫我干什么来着
[I forgot.]
我给忘了
[It should be...]
应该是
Her office is that way.
班主任的办公室在反面
No one is man enough!
没一个爷们
Don't look at me. I don't play.
你可别看我啊 我不会
I'll teach you.
我教你嘛
I can teach you, right?
我可以教你对不对
I'll teach you hands-on.
我教你 手把手教
Nope. Not interested.
不学 不学
Let me tell you,
我跟你说
playing basketball
篮球这项运动
first of all, it shapes up your body,
首先它是很强身健体的
and it has many tricks,
而且它花样很多
many moves,
招式很多
and it's very flexible.
变通术非常高
Did you do your homework?
作业写了吗
No.
没有
These are
没写跟我教你打篮球
irrelevant, OK?
这是两码事好吗
So, I'm telling you,
所以说 我跟你说
you've got to
你一定要跟我
learn to play basketball with me.
好好地学习下篮球
I'll...
我
I'll guide you.
我带带你
I'll guide you, OK?
我带带你还不行吗
I'll teach you hands-on.
我手把手教学的
Hey, seriously,
我跟你说
I'm not going to
这种课时
charge you for it.
费用都不跟你要
Ling Dong,
凌冬
can you help me with this problem?
你能帮我看看这题吗
I've already substituted the formula,
我明明已经代入公式了
still, I couldn't work it out.
但怎么算都算不出来
You've confused the two formulas.
你把两个公式搞混了
The formula for vertical upward throw
垂直上抛的公式
and the formula for free fall
和自由落体的公式
are not the same.
不是一个
Take a closer look at the variables.
你再仔细观察一下变量
OK.
好
Have you completed your tasks today?
你今天任务完成了吗
He's asking you.
问你呢
Have you completed your tasks?
今天任务完成了吗
No.
没有啊
I haven't completed the tasks at all.
根本就没完成任务
The basketball tournament
篮球比赛
is coming soon,
马上就要开始了
and our team is still two players short.
我们队还差两个人
There's no hope for us.
咱班没有希望了
What should I do?
怎么办
There's a solution.
也不是没有办法
What is it?
什么办法
How about this?
这样
Finish memorizing
你先把今天的单词
today's English vocabulary.
背完再说
Roger that, sir!
保证完成任务
Apple, fair,
苹果 公平
limit, tie,
限制 系紧
complete, correct,
完成 音乐会
cosmos, complete,
正确的 星星
thumb, smoker...
开始 连接
Xu Chao,
许超
I remember you were
我记得你高一的时候
on the basketball team last year.
就是篮球队的
Are you interested in joining
所以咱班篮球队
our class's basketball team?
有没有兴趣加入啊
I have to study.
我还要学习呢
The finals are coming up.
这马上期末考试了
I've got no time for the game.
哪有时间打球啊
Got it. I know it all too well.
了解 了解 哥都知道
The top student's notes,
年级第一的笔记
containing a secret speculation sheet,
内含绝密押题宝典
only one copy available.
仅此一份
Really?
真的啊
Really.
真的
Just a basketball team, right?
不就是个篮球队吗
I'm in!
我参加
Come on!
来
What do you want?
你们干吗
Jian Zhiqiang,
简志强
186 cm tall,
身高一八六
nickname "Optimus Prime,"
外号擎天柱
represented your school
初中的时候
in city-level competitions
曾代表过学校
in junior high.
去参加市级比赛
With such good records,
条件这么好
and such a good look,
人还长这么帅
it'd be a pity for you to skip center.
不去打中锋真是可惜了
I won't play.
不打 不打
I'm burnt out from studying lately.
最近学习那么累
Why wouldn't I
我打会儿游戏
go for some online games?
它不香吗
I will join you in Star Leaping.
哥亲自带你上星耀
Honor of Kings?
王者
Not interested.
真没兴趣
I'll personally play with you,
哥亲自陪你玩
and lead you to the highest rank.
这是最高段位了
I'll be with you for the rest of the term.
整个学期都得陪你玩了
Plus a bottle of coke every day.
每天再加一瓶可乐
Deal. Show up to training every day.
成交 每天来训练
No problem.
没问题
I hereby declare,
我宣布
the basketball team of Class 5, Grade 11
高二五班篮球队
is officially established.
正式成立
Good!
好
They are so cool, so handsome!
好帅啊 好帅啊 太帅了
Hurry up and check them out!
赶紧去围观
We are right here!
帅哥在这儿呢
Where are you guys going?
干啥去啊
Class 1 has formed a 188 cm tall boy band.
一班组了个一八八男团
The girls are going to see them.
她们是去一班围观了
What?
什么
Those
这群人胳膊肘
traitors!
给我往外拐
You guys all have excellent taste!
还是你们几个有眼光啊
Hurry up, Xiaohua,
快走 快走 小画 小画
My shoelaces were loose.
刚鞋带掉了
Let's go, hurry.
耽误了这么久 快走
Hurry up, charge!
快走 快走 冲
188 cm boy band,
冲啊 一八八男团
I'm coming!
我来啦
I didn't expect Xiao Xiaohua
没想到肖小画
to be like this as well.
你也是这样的人
They're all 188 cm tall.
人家都是一八八
So what?
一八八一米八八都怎么了
They look good but they suck!
中看不中打
We are the ones with real skills.
我们是实力派
Exactly!
就是
We can't let them look down on us.
不能让他们小瞧我们
Right.
没错
But for the future training,
不过以后的训练
we'll have to rely on you, Jinghui.
还得靠灰哥你了
Don't worry, leave it to me.
放心吧 包在我身上
I, the great me, have mastered
你灰哥我篮球各路招数
all the basketball moves.
集大成于一身
Bravo!
好
I'll work on a problem first.
我先去做个习题
Not focusing on self-study.
自习课不好好上课
What are you doing?
干嘛呢
[Your noisy chatter]
整个年级楼道
[filled the]
就听你们班
[entire hallway.]
叽叽喳喳 叽叽喳喳
[It was like non-stop.]
没完没了的
I now announce,
我现在宣布啊
those who failed more than three subjects
上次考试
in the last exam are not
三门以上不及格的
allowed to participate in the tournament.
全都不许参加篮球比赛
No, no, sir.
不不 不是 主任
Isn't that unreasonable?
这不合理吧
What's unreasonable about it?
有什么不合理的呀
No, last time...
不 上次考试
[What's the duty of a student?]
学生的职责是什么呀
[Answer me.]
回答我
Study.
学习
Sit down.
坐下
[The finals are coming up.]
马上期末考试了啊
[Stay focused, guys.]
大家自己有点压力
[Give everything you've got.]
拿成绩说话
[Xiao Xiaohua, I posted the article.]
肖小画 信是我贴的
[After I accidentally discovered]
在我偶然发现徐梦予
[Xu Mengyu's plagiarism,]
抄袭以后
[I thought she was wrong]
觉得她做错了
[and made]
就将她抄袭的内容
[the whole thing public.]
公之于众
[But I didn't expect]
但我没想到
[things came to this,]
事情会发展成这样
[nor did I expect you to]
更没想到你会因此
[suffer so much because of it.]
受这么大的委屈
[When you were criticized,]
在你受到非议的时候
[I hesitated many times]
我也曾多次犹豫过
[whether to step out or not.]
是不是要站出来
[But in the end, I still didn't have]
但最终我还是没有
[the courage.]
这个勇气
[But you did it,]
可你却做到了
[bravely stepped up and protected me.]
勇敢地站出来保护了我
[Thank you.]
谢谢你
[And, Xiao Xiaohua,]
还有 肖小画
[I'm sorry.]
对不起